Guide to the Douglass Cecil North Papers, 1942-2012 and undated RL.00955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Conferences and Seminars, 1963-2012; 2
  - 1999 May 30, African economic research consortium, Nairobi (Box 39)
  - 1999 June 9 - 11, Introductory note to "17th International Symposium on the New Institutional Economics," Wallerfrangen, Germany (Box 39)
  - 1999 July 29 - 31, "Mental Models in Social Science" conference, University of California, San Diego (Box 40)
  - 1999 Aug. 2, Bechlet symposium (Box 40)
  - 1999 Aug. 2, KNEXUS symposium, Stanford University (Box 40)
  - 1999 Oct. 15 - 16, Chicago - Kent College of Law, Chicago, IL (Box 40)
  - 1999 Oct. 22 – 28, George Mason University School of Law, Public Law Institute for Federal Judges, Tucson, Arizona (Box 91)
  - 1999 Oct. 23 - 24, Judges, Tucson (Box 40)
  - 1999 Nov. SSHA (Social Science History Association) (Box 40)
  - 1999 Nov. 4, Mexico City - Book review (Box 40)
  - 1999 Nov. 5, Milken Institute conference: "California in the 21st Century" (Box 40)
  - 1999 Nov. 5, NASA/KNEXUS "The Mars Mission" (Box 91)
  - 1999 Nov. 18 - 21, AAASS (American Economic Association/ Allied Social Science Association), St. Louis (Box 40)
  - 1999 Nov. 30 - Dec. 1, Fundacion Institucionalidad y Justicia - Dominican Republic (Box 40)
  - 1999 Dec., Network institutional theory, Roskilde University, Denmark (Box 40)
  - 1999 Dec. 7, VenAmCham, Venezuela (Box 40)
  - 1999 Dec. 10 - 11, Royal Netherlands Economic Association, Amsterdam (Box 40)
  - 1999 Dec., AERC "Privatization and Corporate Governance" (Box 40)
  - 1999 ISNIE (Box 91)
  - 2000 Jan. 7 - 9, AEA/ECAAR joint session, Boston, Mass. (Box 40)
  - 2000 Jan., ASSA meeting (Box 40)
  - 2000 Feb. 4 - 6, IFREE annual board meeting, Tucson, AZ (Box 40)
  - 2000 Feb. 7, KNEXUS Symposium, Stanford University (Box 91)
  - 2000 Feb. 24, BBC interview, Adam Salkeld, at Hoover Institution, Stanford, CA (Box 40)
  - 2000 Feb., World Bank conference, Berlin (Box 40)
  - 2000 Mar., Singapore and Hong Kong (Box 40)
  - 2000, Mar. 8 - 10, Milken Institute Nobels session, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - 2000 Mar. 15 - 22, Hong Kong and Singapore, Washington University chancellor's "envoy" trip (Box 40)
  - 2000 Mar. 24, Dinner talk: Greater China Conference, University of Missouri, St. Louis (Box 40)
  - 2000 Mar. 31, Distinguished visitor's program, Indianapolis University, School of Law (Box 40)
  - 2000 Apr. 7 - 9, "Development and the Nation-State in the Crosscurrents of Globalization and Decentralization", Washington University symposium, St. Louis, MO (Box 41)
  - 2000 Apr. 13, University of Wisconsin - LaCrosse: " Uncertainty in a Non-Ergodic World (Box 41)
  - 2000 Apr. 21, "The Process of Economic Change", LEO workshop, Yale Law School, New Haven, CT, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - 2000 May, Oxford Banking Forum, University of Oxford Centre for Socio-Legal Studies (Box 41)
  - 2000 May 4 - 6, "Economies in Evolution - What Can Policy Do?", Bochum, Germany and Barcelona, Spain (Box 41)
  - 2000 May 7 - 9, Keynote Address - The Association of Spanish land Registers, Barcelona, Spain (Box 41)
  - 2000 May 7 - 9, Barcelona (Box 41)
  - 2000 May 19 - 20, Currency unions conference, Hoover Institution, Stanford University (Box 41)
  - 2000 May, Milan – Nobel lecture (Box 91)
  - 2000 June, "Symposium: High Politics and Low Finance", Douglass North and Barry Weingast (Box 41)
  - 2000 June 8, USBSP conference call (Box 41)
  - 2000 June 8, U. S. Business School in Prague: Board of Directors (Box 91)
  - 2000 July 31 - Aug. 2, "Research Agenda", Plan re Stanford symposium (Box 41)
  - 2000 June - July, XIII workshop: "Economics and Law", Italy, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - 2000 July 6 - 9, Fourth world congress of cliometrics, Montreal, Canada (Box 41)
  - 2000 July 14, Girtan College summer guest night, Cambridge (Box 42)
  - 2000 July 15, Center for interdisciplinary studies (Box 42)
  - 2000 July 31 - Aug. 1, KNEXUS research symposium, Stanford, CA, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - 2000 Aug. 3, Third international maritime history conference, Denmark (Box 42)
  - 2000 Aug. 14, "The New Institutionalism in Economics and Sociology", ASA annual meeting, Washington D. C. (Box 42)
  - 2000 Sept. 6 - 9, New wealth and new poverty conference, Milan and Rome, Italy (Box 42)
  - 2000 Sept. 6 - 10, The pope (Box 42)
  - 2000 Sept. 22 - 29, ISNIE, Tubingen (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 13 - 15, Judges (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 13 – 19, The Private Law Institute for Federal Judges – George Mason University School of Law, Tucson, Arizona (Box 91)
  - 2000 Oct. 23, "Complexity and Cognition" symposium, Washington University, School of Law, Center for Interdisciplinary Studies (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 25, "Markets and Institutions" talk, George Mason (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 24 - 26, International conference on global ethos, Tokyo (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 26 - 29, "Cognition, Learning and Social Change", Warrenton, Virginia (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 27 – 28, Cognition, Learning and Social Change. (Box 91)
  - 2000 Oct. 27 - 29, NSF/NBER conference on decentralization, Yorktown Hgts, NY (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct. 31, San Francisco breakfast briefing, Pacific Union Club (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct., Washington University Alumni Club in Japan (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct., Conferences on economic change (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct., First conference, George Mason University (Box 42)
  - 2000 Oct., Whitman College visit (Box 42)
  - 2000 Nov. 9 - 10, Foundation for Teaching Economics, Board of trustees meeting, San Francisco, CA (Box 42)
  - 2000 Nov., Wisconsin, La Crosse (Box 42)
  - 2000 Nov., Harvard Institute for International Development 25th anniversary, Cambridge, MA (Box 42)
  - 2000 Nov. 30 - Dec. 3, "Beliefs, Institutions and Social Change" workshop, Washington University, St. Louis, MO (Box 43)
  - 2000 Dec. 11 - 13, World Bank conference in Tokyo: "Institutions and the Performance of Economics over Time" (Box 43)
  - 2000 Dec. 11 - 13, Tokyo conference - GND (World Bank) (Box 43)
  - 2000 Dec., Paul Edwards-George Mason University – Conference at W. U. (Box 91)
  - 2000, Bertin Martens, "The Cognitive Mechanics of Economic Development: Economic behaviour as a Response to Uncertainty" (Box 43)
  - 2000, CNISS workshop: "Norms in Economics - With Special Reference to Economic Development", Thrainn Eggertson (Box 43)
  - 2001 Jan. 5 - 7, AEA meeting: "Economic Performances of Civilizations", New Orleans, LA (Box 43)
  - 2001 Jan. 23, Claremont McKenna College, Claremont, CA (Box 43)
  - 2001 Feb. 5 - 9, International conference on poverty in Asia, Manila (Box 43)
  - 2001, Mar. 20 - 21, Milken Institute's 2001 Global Conference, Los Angeles, CA (Box 43)
  - 2001 Mar. 30 - 31, "Norms and the Law", Washington University Law School (Box 43)
  - 2001 Apr. 20, "What we know and what we don't know about economic development", The George Seltzer distinguish lecture, University of Minnesota, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - 2001 Apr. 30, IFC Seminar, Harvard (Box 43)
  - 2001 May 5, IFREE meeting, Tucson (Box 43)
  - 2001 May 17, Paul Edwards meeting (Box 44)
  - 2001 May, 2001 Public Choice Society meetings, Mancur Olson lecture series, University of Maryland (Box 44)
  - 2001 July 23, World Bank (Box 44)
  - 2001 July 31 - Aug. 2, Knexus, Stanford (Box 44)
  - 2001 Aug. 8 - 10, Knexus symposium (Box 44)
  - 2001 Sept. 13, Global Development Issues – Nobel Seminar Stockholm, Sweden (Box 91)
    Paper not presented but submitted. Conference cancelled – terrorist attack on US
  - 2001 Sept. 13, "Improving Economic Performance", Stockholm (Box 44)
  - 2001 Sept. 21, Law School meeting, North/Drobak (Box 44)
  - 2001 Sept. 28 - 29, "The Economic Sociology of Capitalism", Cornell University (Box 44)
  - 2001 Sept. 28 - 29, "The Economic Sociology of Capitalism", Cornell University (Box 45)
  - 2001 Oct. 11, "Ethics and Economics", Foligno, Italy (Box 45)
  - 2001 Oct. 16, MEMETRIA, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - 2001 Nov. 15 - 18, SS History, Chicago (Box 45)
  - 2001, Dec. 4, 100th anniversary: Nobel Jubilee, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - 2001 Dec. 4 - 6, Lulea University of Technology (part of Nobel centennial event), Lulea, Sweden (Box 45)
  - 2001 Dec. 12 - 13, "Institute for Federal Judges 2001", School of Law, George Mason University (Box 45)
  - 2001, Open invitations (Box 45)
  - 2001, AEA Meetings (Box 91)
  - 2001, Conferences, Trips, etc. (Box 91)
  - 2002 Jan., AEA meeting (Box 45)
  - 2002 Jan., ASSA Papers Civilizations (Box 45)
  - 2002 Jan. 4 - 7, ASSA meetings, Atlanta (Box 46)
  - 2002 Apr. 10, IMF presentation (Box 46)
  - 2002 Apr. 12, Coase Institute, Chicago, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - 2002 June, ISNIE 2002 conference (Box 46)
  - 2002, Nov. 13 – 14, Globalization, State, Society Conf. Washington University (Box 91)
  - 2002, ISNIE board meeting (Box 46)
  - 2002 – trips, conferences, etc. (Box 91)
  - 2003 Feb. 23 – Ronald Coase Institute Meeting (Box 91)
  - 2003 Sep. 11 – ISNIE Board of Directors (Box 91)
  - 2003 Sep. 15 – 21, Federal Judges Institute: George Mason University: The Wealth of Nations (Box 91)
  - 2003 Sep. 11-13, ISNIE – Seventh Annual Conference, Charles University & Academy of Sciences, Prague, Czech Republic (Box 91)
  - 2004 May 6-8, Bauer Conference, Princeton (Box 91)
  - 2004 May 24-28, Copenhagen Consensus Roundtable (Bjorn Lomborg) (Box 91)
  - 2004 Aug. 23-25, Nobel Laureates Lecture Series – Peking University. (Box 91)
  - 2004 Sep. 1-4, Committee for the Meetings of Nobel Laureates, Lindau (Box 91)
  - 2004 Sep. 30-Oct. 3, ISNIE Meeting (Box 91)
  - 2004 June 15-18, Judges and Bar conference, Hot Springs, VA (Box 91)
  - 2004 Sep., Nobel Meeting Lindau (Box 91)
  - 2005 Jan. 3, Eric Brousseau visit to D.N. (Box 91)
  - 2005 Jan. 7-9, Clio/ASSA Meetings Philadelphia, PA (Box 91)
  - 2005 Feb.-Mar., Bridges – Dialogues Towards a Culture of Peace. Thailand (Box 91)
  - 2005 March 22, KGC Academic Advisory Council Meeting, Stanford U. (Box 91)
  - 2005 April 20, Olin International Business Outlook Conference, W. U. Business School, St. Louis (Box 91)
  - 2005 April 7-8, Inaugural Distinguished Lecture in Economics, Syracuse, NY (Box 91)
  - 2005 May 2-4, ESNIE – Corsica (Box 91)
  - 2005 May 13-19, Turkey (Vac), Balaman (Box 91)
  - 2005 May 25-27, North Carolina Judicial Conference, Asheville, NC (Box 91)
  - 2005 June 23, Torino, Italy, Schofield Conference (Box 91)
  - 2005 June 27, Global Advisory Council Meeting, Dublin, Ireland (Box 91)
  - 2005 Sep. 1-4, Annual APSA Meeting, Washington, D.C. (Box 91)
  - 2005 Oct. 6-8, The Future of the Social Science – meeting II, Cornell University (Box 91)
  - 2006 Feb. 10-11, R. T. Foreign Investment (Box 91)
  - 2006 March 30-31, International Seminar on Latin American Financing and the Role of the National Development Banks (Box 91)
  - 2006 Mar. 28-Apr. 6, 19th Liberty Forum, Improving Performance of Latin America (Box 91)
  - 2006 Apr. 24, Seminar titled "Understanding Economic Growth"– IMF Staff, Washington, D. C. (Box 91)
  - 2006 May 1-2, University of Colorado invited Lecture (Betsy Hoffman ), Denver, CO. (Box 92)
  - 2006 May 4-6, Conference on Manuscript (Weingast, Wallis, Edwards, North), Brian Hooks (Box 92)
  - 2006 May 5-6, American Interests – First Annual Conference: Blindside, How to Anticipate Forcing Events and Wild Cards in Global Politics, Washington, D. C. (Box 92)
  - 2006 May 19-20, FTE Conference, Arizona (Box 92)
  - 2006 May 22-23, Nobel Laureates Forum, Hong Kong (Box 92)
  - 2006 Jun., Contemporary Economic Policy. (Box 92)
  - 2006 June 16-17, Copenhagen Consensus, Georgetown (Box 92)
  - 2006 June 21-22, Petra Conference of Nobel Laureates II, Petra, Jordan (Box 92)
  - 2006 June, Madrid Conference, Spain (Box 92)
  - 2006 July 9-15, China Center for Economics and Business (A Collaborative Research Project), Beijing (Box 92)
  - 2006 Aug. 16-19, Lindau Nobel Laureate Meetings, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2006 Oct. 2-7, "Meet the Authors" conference, Harvard University (Box 92)
  - 2006 Oct. 3-4, Harvard conference on "A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Human History". (Box 92)
  - 2006 Oct. 6-7, Wabash College Lecture, Crawfordsville, IN, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2006 Nov. 17-18, A Conference Honoring Robert W. Fogel (Box 92)
  - 2006 Dec. 2, The Nature of the Judicial Function – George Mason University, Coptiva, FL, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2005-2006, ISNIE (Box 92)
  - 2006, St. Louis Initiative (Box 92)
  - 2007 Mar. 2-3, University of Macau, Chinese Economic Growth: Causes, Prospects and Implications for Macau (Box 92)
  - 2007 Mar. 15-16, Leadership Advisory Council Meeting, KGC, Stanford University (Box 92)
  - 2007 May 4-5, Conference on New Institutional Economics Approach to Policy Reform (Box 92)
  - 2007 May 21-26, ESNIE Annual Meeting, Corsica (Box 92)
  - 2007 Jun. 12-14, Doctor Honoris Causa event at University Paris Sud, Fontenay-aux-Roses, France (Box 92)
  - 2007 Jun. 16-21, Coase Institute, Workshop Reykjavik (Box 92)
  - 2007 Sep. 25, Robert Fogel Lecture, W. U. Law School (Box 92)
  - 2007 Oct. 22-26, Copenhagen Consensus for Latin America, Costa Rica (Box 92)
  - 2007 Feb. The Hong Kong Polytechnic University (Box 92)
  - 2007 Feb. 28, The Chinese University of Hong Kong: "Sun Hung Kai Nobel Lecture" (Box 92)
  - 2007 May 19-22, An Interdisciplinary Conference on "Intellectual Property Rights and Innovative Activity", Madrid, Spain. (Box 92)
  - 2007 Jun. 17-22, ISNIE, Reykjavik, Iceland (Box 92)
  - 2007 Jun. 25-28, AIB Conference "North Honored as Emeritus Scholar and Honorary Fellow", Indianapolis, IN (Box 92)
  - 2007 July 20, The Natural State or Why Effective Reform is so Difficult, Washington D. C. (Box 92)
  - 2007 Oct. 07, Weseda University (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jan. 4-7, AEA Meeting, New Orleans, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jan. 4-6, NBER Conference "Honoring Kenneth Sokoloff", 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jan. 14, Elinor Ostrom, Founding Director, Center for the Study of Institutional Diversity, Arizona State University (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jan. 16, Arizona S. U. "Social Orders and Economic Development: Lessons from History" (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jan, Elinor at ASU (Box 92)
  - 2008 Feb. 15-16, Portland, Oregon (Box 92)
  - 2008 Feb., Vatter Lecture (Box 92)
  - 2008 Mar. 6-15, Singapore, Phillipines (Box 92)
  - 2008 Mar. 6-18 Singapore/Manila Trip (Box 92)
  - 2008 Apr. 10-13, Islam and Economic Underdevelopment, George Mason University (Box 92)
  - 2008 Apr. 11-13, Mercatus Conference on Kuran manuscript (Box 92)
  - 2008 April 15-16, PREM Conference (World Bank), Washington D. C. (Box 92)
  - 2008 Apr. 23, Chinese Delegation Meeting, Washington University, St. Louis (Box 92)
  - 2008 Apr., Initiative on Government and Development (Box 92)
  - 2008 Apr., World Bank (Box 92)
  - 2008 May 25-30, Copenhagen Consensus (Box 92)
  - 2008 Jun. 17-19, Conference of Nobel Laureates – Petra IV (Box 92)
    D. N. canceled because of scheduling conflict
  - 2008 Jul. 30, IMF Seminar (Box 92)
  - 2008 Aug. 20-23, 3rd Meeting in Economic Sciences. Lindau Meetings (Box 92)
  - 2008 Sep., Conference on Twenty Years of Transition in Central Europe (Box 92)
  - 2008, Oct. 18, U. of Rochester, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - 2008 Oct. 21, Stanford Pioneers in Science. (Box 92)
  - 2008, Oct. 29 – Nov. 1, Miller Upton Forum, Beloit College., 3 folders (Box 92)
  - 2008 Nov. 7-8, Understanding Long-Run Economic Growth: A Conference honoring the contributions of Kenneth Sokoloff (Box 92)
  - 2008 Nov., Coase Institute Meeting (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec. 10, Analyzing China's Economic Development, Hong Kong Polytechnic (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec. 12, Violence and Social Orders: A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Human History, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec., Coase Institute Workshop, China, 3 folders (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec. 15, HSBC Nobel Laureate Forum at CCER (China Center for Economic Research) (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec., China (Box 92)
  - 2008 Dec., ISNIE (Box 92)
  - 2008, Petra Conference (Box 92)
  - 2008, Copenhagen Consensus (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 2, CNISS (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 2-3, Law School Conference (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 2-3, "The Economics and Law of Innovation", W. U. School of Law, St. Louis, MO (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 4, "Excellence in Achievement Award", San Francisco, CA (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 12-19, Trip to D. C. (Box 92)
  - 2009 Apr. 23, Rhodes College (Box 92)
  - 2009 May 20, Naples (Box 92)
  - 2009 May 21-23, "Il Destino della Democrazia, Relativismo e Universalizzione", Napoli, Italy (Box 92)
  - 2009 Jun. 5-6, "Transformation, Economic Growth and Convergence in Poland and Other Central and Eastern European Countries", Warsaw, Poland (Box 92)
  - 2009 Sep. 3-6, APSA Annual Meeting, Toronto (Box 92)
  - 2009 Sep., Developing Institutions in Limited Access Orders, Washington (Box 92)
  - 2009 Nov., Workshop – Case Western Reserve University, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - 2009 Dec. 4-5, Coase Conference (Box 93)
  - 2009 Dec. 4-5, Ronald Coase Centennial Conference, Chicago, Ill. (Box 93)
  - 2009-2012, Copenhagen Consensus (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jan. 3-4, ASSA 2010 (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jan. 4-5, Coase Centennial U. Chicago (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jan. 8-10, LAO Conference, Stanford University (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jan. 15-16, WB Workshop, Stanford U. (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jan., Forum for Health Economics & Policy. Goldmanm Dana P. (Box 93)
  - 2010 Feb. 5-7, APSA 2010, Washington D. C. (Box 93)
  - 2010 Apr. 15-16, 2010 Missouri Conference on History (Box 93)
  - 2010 Apr. 26-30, Seminars: CNISS, CRESS – Applied Microeconomics (Box 93)
  - 2010 May, Moscow Conference (Box 93)
    Correspondence on video from the conference
  - 2010 May, Symposium: Culture and Economic Development, Moscow 2010 (Box 93)
  - 2010 May, "The Role of Culture in Understanding the Process of Economic and Social Change", Samuel P. Huntington Memorial Conference (Box 93)
  - 2010 May, van Bavel, Bas, Dijkman, Jessica, Kuijpers, Erika and Zuiderduijn, Jaco. The Organization of Markets as a Key Factor in the Rise of Holland. (Box 93)
  - 2010 May, Video Conference - "Limited Access Order: Launch Workshop for Case Studies" (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jun. 2-4, "Tenth Annual International Seminar on Policy Challenges for the Financial Sector", World Bank, Washington, D. C. (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jul. 19-23, Conference on Chinese Economic Development, Chicago, Ill (Box 93)
  - 2010 Jul. 19-23, U. of Chicago Conference (Box 93)
  - 2010 Sep. 19-21, The Property Rights Conference Papers. Evolution of the Property Rights Related to Land and Natural Resources (Box 93)
  - 2010 Sep. 19-22, Property Rights Conference, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 93)
  - 2010 Sep. 20-21, "Lincoln Institute: Property Rights Conference" (Box 93)
  - 2010 Sep. 20-21, Conference Papers for the Property Rights Conference (Box 93)
  - 2010 Nov. 4-6, Conference Honoring D. N., W. U. (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jan., AEA Meeting 2011. Declined. (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jan. 6-9, ASSA Conference Session (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jan. 7-9, ASSA, Denver, CO. (Box 93)
    There is a note labeling Peter G. Klein for this folder.
  - 2011 Mar. 31-Apr. 2, BHC Business History Meeting (Box 93)
  - 2011 May 13, ISNIE 2011 Board Meeting (Box 93)
  - 2011 May 16-19, 3rd Nobel Laureates Symposium on Global Sustainability for Human Development (Box 93)
  - 2011 May 16-19, Nobel Laureate Symposium on Global Sustainability (Box 93)
  - 2011 May, Asia Pacific Forest Partnership (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jun. 9-12, 2011 North American Summer Meeting of the Econometric Society, Washington University in St. Louis (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jun. 17, ISNIE 2011 (Box 93)
  - 2011 Jun. 21-22, Mokyr Conference (Box 93)
  - 2011 Aug. 23-27, 4th Meeting of the Winners of the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences, Lindau, Germany (Box 93)
  - 2011 Sep., Thrainn Eggertsson's Festschrift (Box 93)
  - 2011 Oct., Beloit College (Box 93)
  - 2011 Oct., 2011 Upton Forum (Box 93)
  - 2011 Dec. 1-3, EMNET – Vienna, Berlin, Cyprus (Box 93)
  - 2012 Jan.-March, Stanford report (Box 93)
  - 2012 Apr., Thrainn Eggertsson – Iceland (Box 93)
  - 2012 May 7-11, Copenhagen Consensus (Box 93)
  - 2012 Jul. 26-29, Ostrom Conference (Box 93)
- Initiatives and Academic Life, 1942-2012 and undated; 3
  This series contains select documents on North's academic life and both academic and political initiatives. Highlights for his initiatives include a set of North's notes from research and consultancy trips to Brazil and Venezuela; North's work for the Bradley Foundation, the Task Force on Economic Transition (1997), Microsoft, and the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights; his correspondence with the Nobel Prize organization; Copenhagen Consensus; and St. Louis Initiative.
  Series also contains North's autobiographical material, his autobiographical sketches, versions of his vita from 1987 till 2009, and calendars. For about his last 25 years of life, he used to spend his summer and winter holidays with his wife Elisabeth Case in their summer house in Benzonia, Michigan.
  Biographical material also contains non-academic aspects of his life. North noted in a biographical sketch that research "has been intermingled with a variety of activities that have complemented that central preoccupation and enriched my life. I continue to be a photographer; I have enjoyed fishing and hunting with a close friend; and have owned two ranches, first in northern California and then in the state of Washington. I learned to fly an airplane, and had my own airplane during the 1960s. I have always taken seriously good food and wine. In addition, music has continued to be an important part of my life." This series contains materials documenting his interest in photography, art and music.
  This series also contain Fannie Batt's materials including her own correspondence. Rubenstein received her material labeled as "Not D. North". Material gives a picture into the nature of Fannie Batt's work for D. North, on her other work and on her routines. Note that North's correspondence was carried by Fannie Batt since 1990s, and mainly through her email address.
  - Addendum to Nobel Autobiography for Douglass C. North, 2005 (Box 98)
  - Address Book, 1997-2000 (Box 98)
  - Addresses, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Annual Report to Congress – Military Power of the People's Republic of China, Dept. of Defense., 2007 (Box 98)
  - Art Work, 2008 (Box 98)
  - Autobiography – nobelprize.org and 2008 correspondence (Box 98)
  - Bradley Foundation, 2004 (Box 98)
  - Brazil: Research and Travel Lecture notes on the Vargas Institute, undated (Box 47)
  - Brazil: Research and Travel: Official report, 1961 (Box 47)
  - Brazil: Original notes and memoranda on trip to Rio, undated (Box 47)
  - Brazilian development, April 30, 2001 (Box 47)
  - Notes on Brazil Trip (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation: 1989-1990 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation Accounts, 1992-1993 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation Grants, 1992-1999 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation 1997-1998 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation Report, 1986-1993 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation 1990-1991 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation Accounts, 1991-1992 (Box 47)
  - Bradley Foundation 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Calendar, 2003 (Box 98)
  - Calendar, 2005-2006 (Box 98)
  - Calendar, 2007-2009 (Box 98)
  - Calendar, 2010-2012 (Box 98)
  - Center for the History of Freedom, Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 47)
  - The Emergence of Social, Political, and Economic Institutions correspondence, Jan. 1984-Dec.1985 (Box 48)
  - The Emergence of Social, Political, and Economic Institutions Charge to working groups; first statement and preliminary comments on charge by participants, 1985 and undated (Box 48)
  - CNISS Annual Report 2008/2009 (Box 98)
  - CNISS North Research Fund, 2010 (Box 98)
  - Coca Cola Community Water Partnership Project (St. Louis Initiative, Copenhagen Consensus), 2006 (Box 98)
  - The Emergence of Social, Political, and Economic Institutions comments on committee members, 1985 (Box 48)